(ゲンゴ)サスケが里に戻ったとたん 誰も
お前には目もくれなくなった。
The minute Sasuke returned
to the village,
people stopped paying attention
to you.
(サイ)くだらないな。
How trivial.
僕が そんなことを
気にしているとでも？
Do you think something like
that would bother me?
You might consider yourself
a member of Team 7,
(ゲンゴ)お前は 第七班の一員だった
つもりかもしれないが→
but I wonder what they think?
果たして 向こうは
どう思っていたかな？
安っぽい口車なんかに
乗せられるものか！ 僕は…。
Do you really think I'd fall
for your cheap persuasions?
I'm…
Dark Clouds
(朧)あれが サイ殿が最後に
立ち寄った宿屋でござるな？
That's the inn that Lord Sai
last stopped by…
(シカマル)あぁ。
それに もう少し上を見ろ。
Yeah.
Also, look slightly above it.
(シカマル)帳の里に通じる
唯一の関所だ。
That's the only checkpoint leading
into the village of Tobari.
あそこを うまく通り抜けなきゃ
里には入れねえ。
Unless we get past it,
we can't get to the village.
(鏃)だからって
こんな格好する必要なかったし。
Sure, but is this get-up, like,
really necessary?
(朧)似合ってるでござるよ 鏃。
はぁ…。
It looks very becoming
on you, Soku.
(シカマル)あのな
炭屋の通行証を手に入れるのも→
Look, I had to bend over backwards to
get a coal vendor's traveling permit.
骨折りだったんだぞ。
他に 関所を通るいい方法が
あるなら 教えてほしいもんだぜ。
If you have any better ideas on getting
past the checkpoint, let me know.
確かに これなら→
We can humbly guarantee that
敵をごまかせること
請け合いでござるな。
we will be able to deceive
the enemy's eyes with this.
見張りを全員 殺せば
関所なんて 簡単に通れるし。
Like, if we kill all of the lookouts,
it will be easy to pass
through the checkpoint!
そんなことして→
It would spell trouble
if we do that
木ノ葉がからんでることが
バレたら やっかいだろうが。
and they found out
the Leaf's involved.
それに サイの部隊も このあたりで
全滅したんだ。 敵を甘く見るな。
Besides, Sai's entire team
was killed around here.
Don't underestimate the enemy.
(鏃)ぐずぐずしてたら 敵に
気づかれる危険が増えるだけだし。
If we linger too long,
we'll only, like, up the chances
of the enemy noticing us.
(シカマル)２人とも 聞いてくれ。
Both of you, listen up.
いいか？ 俺たちは お互いに→
Look, I think it's crucial that
we trust each other.
信頼し合わなければ
ならないと思う。
信頼関係ってのは→
And trust first begins with
having faith in your partner.
まず 自分が相手を
信じるところから始まるんだ。
なんか変な本でも読んだし？
Did you get that out of, like,
some weird book?
シカマル殿は これでも
リーダーらしくあろうと→
Lord Shikamaru is doing
his utmost to act like our leader.
一生懸命なのでざるよ。
(シカマル)俺の心の機微を
勝手に読むんじゃねえ！
Quit trying to analyze me!
とにかく この作戦には チームワーク…。
Anyway! This mission
requires teamwork—
Huh?!
What's the big idea?!
何の真似だ!?
よく見るし。
Like, take a good look.
黙の忍か！
Land of Silence shinobi?!
Soku!
鏃！ チッ…。
勝手に動くんじゃねえ！
Don't take action by yourself!
こういうのは
私のほうが得意だし！
I'm better at, like,
this sort of thing!
はぁっ！
(鏃)やったし！
I did it!
(シカマル)はぁ… おい おい！
Hey, c'mon.
変装が ムダになったじゃねえか。
You just ruined our disguise.
やっかいなことに
なったでござるな。
This has turned out to be
a problematic occurrence.
こりゃ
１から作戦の練り直しだな。
Well… I guess it's back to
square one for our strategy.
何にするね？
What'll you have?
Can I have a water?
水 もらえるか？
You can have all you want.
お好きなだけ。
Anyway…
ところで このあたりに
帳の関所があるって聞いたんだが。
I heard the checkpoint
to Tobari is around here.
よそ者に話すことは何もないね。
I've got nothing to say to outsiders.
KNIGHT
(シカマル)鬼殺しですね。
The "demon killer"?
ほう… これがわかるかね？
Oh…You know the game?
ここ いいですか？
May I sit in?
こんな場所で
相手にめぐり会えるとは…。
What luck finding an opponent
in these parts.
A welcome sight indeed.
地獄に仏とは このことですな。
こちらへは お一人で？
Are you traveling alone?
帳の里に
忍の依頼に来たんですが→
I've come to the village of Tobari
to request shinobi assistance.
身元の調査だ なんだと
待たされまして。
But they're checking
my background and what not,
so, I've had to wait,
as you can see.
このざまですよ。
帳の里ですか。
The Village of Tobari?
商売で 一度 行ってみたいと
思ってはいるんですけど。
I've been wanting to do
some business there.
出入りのチェックが
やたらと厳しいので→
Going in and out of there
is such hassle.
PASSAGE
Unless you have this pass,
it's probably impossible.
この通行証がないと
無理でしょうな。
(シカマル)まいったな！
You got me!
その手があったか。
Didn't expect that move!
PASSAGE
Time's up…
待ったなしですよ。
それにしても どうして
黙の国を選んだんです？
By the way…
Why did you choose
the Land of Silence?
There are other lands that
accept shinobi requests.
忍の依頼を受ける国なら
他にもありそうですが。
Well, it's the price.
そりゃ 値段ですよ。
After all, I don't mind
who does the work itself,
やることさえ やってくれたら
黙だろうが 木ノ葉だろうが→
whether it's the Silence
or the Hidden Leaf.
どっちだって
かまいませんからね。
忍なんてのは しょせん
使い捨ての歩みたいなもんですよ。
After all, shinobi are merely
appendages that you use,
then discard.
ちょっと 失礼！
Please excuse me!
(シカマル)作戦をぶち壊すつもりか!?
Are you trying to sabotage
our strategy?
(鏃)あんなやつを
のさばらせておくから→
It's because we let guys like that
say whatever they want that,
いつまでも 忍は
見下されたままなんだし！
like, shinobi are always
looked down upon.
だからって 殺すことはねえだろ！
That's no reason to kill him.
ちょっと脅してやろうと
思っただけだし。
I just wanted to
shake him up a little.
仲間を信頼してないのは
そっちだし！
Like, you're the one
who doesn't trust us.
だったら
もう少し慎重に行動しろ。
Then act with more caution.
文句でもあんのか？
Got any complaints?
慎重にやりすぎて
任務をしくじるなんて→
No way I'll mess up a mission
by being, like, overcautious!
私は 絶対にごめんだし！
あいつ…。
That girl…
なんか妙に焦ってねえか？
Isn't she acting too rash?
鏃は 世の中が
平和になるにつれて→
More than anyone,
Soku fears that peace in the land
忍の存在意義が
失われつつあることに→
will spell the end of
a shinobi's existence.
誰よりも危機感を
抱いているのでござる。
今回の任務を成功させて→
I presume she is determined
to make this mission a success
忍の価値を世間に
知らしめたいのでござろう。
to prove the value of shinobi
to the world.
多くの血を流して→
So much blood was shed
to achieve this long-sought peace.
ようやく手にした
平和だってのに→
それが気に入らねえとは
贅沢な話だぜ。
It's ridiculous that
some people can't stomach it.
(朧)シカマル殿は 先の大戦で→
Lord Shikamaru, you proved
your mettle and worth as a shinobi
己の才覚を存分に
発揮できたかもしれませんが→
in the last Great Ninja War.
彼女には それがない。
But she's never had
a chance to do so.
遅れてきた世代の
悲しさでござろうな。
Such is the sorrow of
the generation that came too late.
朧 あんたはどうなんだよ？
Ro, what about you?
あんたも
いろいろ経験してきたんだろ？
You've experienced a lot,
haven't you?
拙者は
ただの死に損ないでござる。
I simply escaped death,
that is all.
Everyone, do not move!
全員 その場を動くな！
これから きさまらの身元を
改めさせてもらう。
We're going to confirm
your identity.
この建物から
出ることは許さん！
You will not be allowed
to leave the building!
Hey!
何があった？
谷底に落ちた忍が→
What happened?
The shinobi in the ravine were,
like, discovered.
発見されたみたいだし。
チッ 思ったより
動きが早いな。
They move faster than I thought.
やめろ！ ここで
騒ぎを起こすのはまずい！
Don't!
– We can't make a scene now.
– I'm just waiting for my shogi partner!
じゃあ どうするし？
だから今 考えてる。
– Then what do we do?!
–  Move!
– I'm thinking…
– You two!
(朧)２人とも。
(２人)うん？
Over here!
こっちでござる。
ふざけんな コラ！
きさま 何してる？
How dare you!
What are you doing?
(朧)おかげで助かったでござる。
We owe our lives to you.
(コモリ)礼には及ばねえぜ。
No thanks necessary.
I hate those guys from Tobari.
おいら あの帳のやつらが
大嫌いなんだ。
They're always so arrogant.
いつも偉そうに
いばりやがって。
おいら コモリってんだ。
よろしくな。
I'm Komori. Nice to meet you.
Uh, we're…
俺たちはだな…。
おっと。
Whoa!
無理に
話さなくたっていいんだぜ。
You don't have to tell me.
お互い 探られたくねえハラの
１つや２つ あるってもんよ。
We all have a thing or two
we keep hidden, eh?
コモリ 俺たちは帳の里に
行きたいんだ。
Komori, we want to go
to the Village of Tobari.
関所を抜ける方法を
何か知らないか？
Do you know of a way
to get past the checkpoint?
そいつは難問だな。
Now that's a tough question
to answer.
なんでまた あんなところに
行きたがるんだい？
But why do you want
to go there?
We've got some minor business
to take care of.
ちょっと野暮用でね。
シッ 誰かいる。
Someone's here!
なんだ ネズミか
おどかすなよ。
What? It's just a mouse.
Don't scare me like that!
おい 関所を抜ける方法が
見つかるまで→
What don't you understand
about waiting until we find a way
to get through the checkpoint?
待てってのがわかんねえのか？
のんびりしてたら→
Like, if we take our time,
we'll lose the chance to kill Gengo!
ゲンゴを殺るチャンスを
逃すだけだし！
１人で行くのは危険でござる。
It's too dangerous to go alone.
勝手な行動は許さねえぞ。
You are not to act alone!
私はただ
実力を証明したいだけだし。
I just want to,
like, prove my ability.
それを くだらないルールで
邪魔されたらたまんないし。
And I won't be held back
by stupid rules!
ガキじゃねえんだ
遊び半分でやられちゃ→
Grow up!
This isn't some kind of game!
迷惑なんだよ。
めんどくさ。
What a drag.
はあ？
これなら黙の国のほうが→
What?!
Maybe I'll have more freedom
in the Land of Silence.
まだ好き勝手に
できそうだし。
めったなことを
言うものではござらん。
You mustn't say
such reckless things.
おい まさかお前 妙なことを
考えてるんじゃねえだろうな？
Hey, you're not…
getting any weird ideas, are you?
里抜けは大罪だ。
Deserting the village is
a serious crime.
抜け忍は
地の果てまで追いかけて→
Rogue Ninja are hunted down
to the ends of the earth
必ず報いを受けさせるのが忍の掟。
and are always punished to
the harshest extent of shinobi law.
それを知らないはずはねえよな？
You're aware of that, aren't you?
シカマル殿
鏃も本気ではござらん。
Lord Shikamaru, Soku isn't serious.
そうでござるよな？
関係ないし！
Isn't that so?
Like I care!
まだ話は終わってねえぞ。
Hey, we're not done here!
Oh?
あれ？ ご機嫌斜めかい？
In a bad mood?
あんたには関係ないし。
Like, it's none of your business.
何があったか知らないけどさ
腐っちまったらおしまいだぜ。
I don't know what happened,
but it's over if
you get discouraged.
俺だって 今はこんな仕事を
押し付けられてるけどよ→
Look at me.
I'm forced to do jobs like this…
いつか自分のでっかい宿屋を
持ってやんだ！
But one day, I'm gonna have
a huge inn of my own!
誰も聞いてないし。
Like, no one asked you.
ハァ… あいつ→
That kid…
自分が何をすべきか
わかってんだろうな？
I hope she knows what
she's supposed to do here.
鏃なら きっと心配ないでござる。
There's no need to worry
about Soku.
私はただ この力を
役に立てたかっただけだし。
I just wanted to, like,
make my power useful.
お前 忍だったんだな。
So, you were a shinobi.
誰にも内緒だし。
わ… わかってるって。
It's a secret.
I-I know that!
里の人間は平和に慣れすぎて→
Everyone in the village
has gotten used to peace,
みんな臆病になってしまったし。
and they're too timid.
これなら 黙に下ったほうが
よっぽどマシだし。
Like, at this rate,
I should have just gone to
the Land of Silence.
まさか
里に刃向かう気じゃないよな？
Surely, you're not going to
desert your village?
それって たしか 重罪なんだろ？
Isn't that a serious crime?
そんなの わかってるし。
Like, yeah, I know that.
話したら 少しすっきりした。
I feel a little better
after talking to you.
仲間のとこ戻るし。
そっか。
I'm going back to the guys.
I see…
じゃあ オイラも一緒に
ついてってやるよ。
I'll come with you!
べつに ついてこなくていいし。
You don't have to.
オイラ 怒られ慣れてるからさ→
I'm used to getting scolded,
謝るのは得意なんだぜ。
so I'm really good
at apologizing!
(シカマル)朧
お前も あいつの目を見ただろ？
Ro, you saw her eyes too, right?
(朧)考えすぎでござるよ。
You are overthinking this.
もし鏃が
本気で里を抜けるつもりなら→
If Soku is serious about
deserting the village…
あいつの口を封じなきゃならねえ。
できるか？
we have to silence her.
Can you do it?
できるかって聞いてんだ。
I'm asking you,
would you be able to do it?
抜け忍は大罪でござる。
Desertion is a serious crime.
もし鏃が
本気で抜けるつもりなら→
If Soku is serious,
拙者に迷いはござらん。
I shall not falter.
やっぱりだし！
あいつら 仲間でも何でもないし。
I knew it!
Like, they're not comrades
or anything!
待てよ！
Wait!
鏃…。
Soku!
もう 私の居場所は
どこにもないし。
I don't have a place
where I belong anymore.
もし 関所まで
黙のやつらに見つからない→
What if…
I told you that
there's a safe route
安全なルートがあるって言ったら→
to get to the checkpoint
without being discovered?
一か八か 試してみるかい？
Are you willing to risk it?
((コモリ : 少し遠回りになるけど
川に沿っていけば→
It's the long way,
but if you follow the river,
you'll reach the checkpoint
without being seen.
(誰にも見つからずに
関所まで たどり着けるはずだ))
(シカマル)おい。
あっ！
Hey!
こんなところで何してる？
What are you doing here?
U-Uh… I was looking for
the mouse that got away.
え… えっと
逃げたネズミを探して…。
鏃を見なかったか？
Have you seen Soku?
I-I didn't see anything!
オ… オイラ 何も見てないよ。
何事でござるか？
あ…。
What is going on?
おい！
俺の目を見て もう一度答えろ。
Hey!
Look at me in the eye
and answer me again!
鏃は どこへ行った？
知らないってば！
Where did Soku go?
I'm tellin' you I don't know!
まさか 関所に向かったのか？
Don't tell me…
Is she heading for
the checkpoint?
里抜けか？ そうなんだな？
Did she desert?
That's it, isn't it?
鏃が里を抜けるなど
ありえないことでござる。
That's inconceivable!
Soku would not desert the village!
それを確かめるには
鏃を捕まえて 直接聞くしかねえ。
To find out, we need to catch Soku
and ask her directly.
止まれ！ 貴様 何者だ？
Stop!
Why you—! Who are you?!
里を抜けてきた。
I deserted my village!
この国で存分に腕を振るいたい。
I want my skills to be of use here,
for this land!
If you interfere, you're dead!
邪魔すれば命はねえぞ。
お前みたいなガキが 抜け忍だと？
A Rogue Ninja?
A kid like you?
歳は関係ないし。
実力が すべてだし。
Like, age doesn't matter.
Ability is everything.
Well, at least you talk the talk!
口だけは一人前のようだな。
あっ！
You won't walk away with just
a wound on your leg the next time.
次は
足のケガくらいじゃ済まないし。
わ… 悪く思うな。
D-Don't take this the wrong way.
このところ しつこく嗅ぎまわる
ネズミが多くてな。
We've had a lot of rats
sniffing around lately.
たしか この間も。
Just recently…
えぇ 木ノ葉の暗部が。
Yeah…
It was ANBU from
the Hidden Leaf.
お前は その歳で
里抜けをしようというのか？
You intend on deserting
your village at your age?
古臭い掟に うんざりしたんだし。
I'm just sick of
old-fashioned rules.
私の腕なら
仲間にして損はないし。
Like, with my skills,
you won't regret making me
one of you.
すばらしい 気に入ったぞ。
Great! I like you!
それにしても
おもしろい技を使う。
Well, you certainly have
an interesting technique.
偵察に出していた部下が２人
やられたばかりでな。
Two of my men who were
on reconnaissance were just killed.
貴様のその技が ２人をやった傷と
そっくりなのは→
Your technique inflicts the same kind
of wound that killed them.
I wonder why?
どういう訳か説明してもらおうか。
Would you care to explain?
雲行きが怪しくなってきたな
お嬢ちゃん。
Things aren't looking good for you…
are they, young lady?
そいつなら問題ありません。
She's okay.
コモリ！
黙っていて悪かったな。
Komori?
Sorry I didn't say anything.
お前が信用できるかどうか
確かめる必要があったんだ。
I had to test you to make sure
we could trust you.
フン
こいつは俺たちの仲間を殺した。
She killed our comrades.
信用できん。
いきなり襲ってきたから→
We can't trust her.
They attacked out of nowhere,
I had no choice.
しかたなかったし。
けど 仲間とケンカ別れして→
I had a fight with my partners,
里を抜ける決心したんだし。
and I've made up
my mind to leave.
隊長 俺はずっと
こいつのことを見張ってました。
Captain, I've watched her
all this time.
仲間割れしたのも本当です。
She really did split off
from her group.
But I can't just take
your word for it.
しかし お前の言葉だけではな。
Like, if you don't believe me,
信じないのなら この場で
全員と刺し違えても構わないし。
I don't mind if we fight it out,
right here.
We found you, Soku!
見つけたぞ 鏃！
So, you were pulling the strings,
all this time, Komori!
やっぱり お前が糸を
引いてやがったか コモリ！
案外 早かったじゃないか。
だが 周りをよく見ろ。
You were pretty quick.
But take a good look around you.
お前らに勝ち目はないぞ！
There's no way you can win!
おい 里抜けは大罪ってことくらい
あんたらでも わかるよな？
Hey!
Even you understand the gravity
of deserting a village, don't you?
今すぐ そいつを
引き渡してもらおうか。
Hand her over to us right now.
If you interfere,
I won't go easy on you!
邪魔するなら 容赦しないし！
Will you turn her over, or not?
引き渡すのか？ 渡さねえのか？
フッフッ おもしろい。
Interesting…
貴様の覚悟が本物かどうか
証明するチャンスだぞ。
This is your chance to prove
that you're serious.
俺も加勢するぜ！
I'll help you!
I don't need your help!
助けはいらない！
これは私の問題だし！
This is my problem!
なっ！
Lord Shikamaru,
I implore you to think it over!
シカマル殿 考え直すでござる。
Soku has her reasons.
鏃にも事情があってのこと。
Don't be reckless!
早まってはいけませぬ！
Are you going to betray me too?
てめえも裏切ろうってのか！
Y-You misunderstand!
ご 誤解でござる！
Then you're…first!
だったら てめえが先だ！
うっ… シカマル… 殿。
Lord…Shikamaru!
てめえら ２人まとめて…。
You two…together—!
うぐっ！
Soku… You didn't...
鏃… まさか。
ハァハァ…。
うぉ～！
ハァハァ。
よくやった。
You did well!
I don't sense any chakra.
He's dead.
チャクラの反応がありません。
死んでます。
やったな 鏃。
You did it, Soku!
なかなか使えそうなやつだ 来い。
You'll be quite useful. Come.
You're one of us now.
これで お前も 俺たちの仲間だ。
いくつか取り調べを
受けてもらうことになるけど→
You'll have to go through
some rounds of questioning,
すぐに解放されるさ。
but you'll be released right away.
In exchange for the intel
that you possess—
お前が持ってる情報と
引き換えに…。
I'm gonna have you, like,
sleep for a while.
しばらくの間
眠っていてもらうし。
Damn it, that was rough!
プハ～ まったく
ひでえ目にあったぜ。
うまくいき申したな。
It went quite well.
Soku said she'll make it
seem like we're dead.
鏃のやつ 仮死状態にするだけ
とか言ってたくせに→
十分 痛えじゃねえか。
But that hurt a lot.
We owe that young boy
some thanks too.
あの少年にも感謝でござるな。
What? It's just a mouse.
((なんだ ネズミか))
Earlier, I used chakra to fake
a shinobi's presence.
(朧)あのとき
チャクラの錯誤効果を利用して→
忍がいるように
見せかけたでござる。
And his unexpected reaction
was our lucky break.
思わず反応しちまったのが
運の尽きだったな。
An ordinary kid wouldn't have
reacted to chakra like he did.
ただのガキなら
チャクラに反応するはずはねえ。
And he performed unerringly
as we predicted.
まんまと こちらの読みどおりに
動いてくれ申した。
鏃の言っていた不満
半分は本心でござった。
But what Soku bemoaned…
She meant half of what she said.
もし本気で
里を抜ける気になれば→
If she had been really serious,
いつでも我々を殺せたでござる。
その危険は
感じなかったでござるか？
信頼関係ってのは まず自分が→
相手を信じるところから始まる
って言ったろ？
(朧)さすがでござるな。
(シカマル)ヘッ 鏃には言うなよ。
調子にのるといけねえから。
全部聞こえてるし。
シカマルも意外と考えが甘いし。
どういう意味だよ？ まさか→
本気で撃つつもりじゃ
なかったよな？
もう一度 試してみてもいいし。
そいつは また今度な。
それよし いけそうか？
(鏃)カギは開けておいたから
すぐに戻ればバレないし。
上出来だ。